# **Christopher Hedlund**

Hillsboro, OH | christopher.m.hedlund@gmail.com | 443.417.3490

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-hedlund-a6013b8a">https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-hedlund-a6013b8a</a> | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/swedishkinda">https://github.com/swedishkinda</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://swedishkinda.github.io/Portfolio/">https://swedishkinda.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

## SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary Web Developer with a passion for front-end development. Experience building websites with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and jQuery from start to finish and seeing strong outcomes when deploying. Adapts well to diverse working environments and collaborating with teams. Brings experience obtained through meticulous design. Prepared to excel in solving complex problems.

#### SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript ES5/ES6, jQuery, API's, JSON, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and Flexbox

Databases: Mongo, SQL, FireBase

Miscellaneous: Microsoft Office, Git/Github, Adobe Suite

#### PROJECTS

ED SITE: https://github.com/swedishKinda/Educational\_Site https://swedishkinda.github.io/Educational\_Site

- An educational website with different kinds of interactives.
- **Technologies:** Bootstrap, Flexbox, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, and Slick.

My Chef: <a href="https://github.com/swedishkinda/My-Chef/">https://github.com/swedishkinda/My-Chef/</a> <a href="https://swedishkinda.github.io/My-Chef/">https://swedishkinda.github.io/My-Chef/</a>

- JavaScript application that essentially returns a list of drink or meal recipes based on a given ingredient.
- Technologies: AJAX calls to two separate API's, JQuery library for "Slick" carousel, and "modal" alerts

Liri Node App: https://github.com/swedishkinda/liri-node-app https://youtu.be/v3Cd6raLesY

- App where the user can search for a song on Spotify, a movie on IMDB, or for a concert on Bandsintown.
- Technologies: JavaScript ES6, Node.js, and NPMs FS, Inquirer, Spotify, Axios, Moment, and Dotenv.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Accelerate Education Apr. 2020 - Feb. 2024

Front-End Web Developer

- Develop websites to be used in online learning environments.
- Display in depth knowledge of jQuery, JavaScript ES5/ES6, HTML5, CSS3, and Adobe Suite.

Uber/Caviar/Postmates Mar. 2015 - Current

Associate/Driver

**US Aquatics**: Beltsville, MD Apr. 2011– Mar. 2015

Regional Manager (Philadelphia Area)

- Interacted with clients to ensure quality customer service. And worked with local governmental operations to see that all standards are met.
- Performed the ability to work independently without direct oversight, but in an overall team environment.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Pennsylvania LPS Coding Bootcamp, Philadelphia, PA

Certificate Full-Stack Web Development

University of Maryland, Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD

- Mechanical Engineering and Environmental Science

Oct. 2019

Dec. 2007